Guide to C. Mehrl Bennett Artwork and Visual Poetry, 2006-2018 SPEC.RARE.0217
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
C. Mehrl Bennett Artwork and Visual Poetry
2006-2018
SPEC.RARE.0217
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
0.42 Cubic feet
As of 2017, C. Mehrl Bennett is a multi-media artist, performer, and writer of fluxus scores and experimental poetry in Columbus, Ohio. C. Mehrl Bennett Artwork and Visual Poetry contains small visual poetry booklets, artistamps, artist books, and printouts and compact discs of multi-media and word artwork created by Bennett between 2006 and 2018. Some of the materials are collaborations with other visual artists and experimental writers.
(1) 5” letter document box; (1) flat box
Bennett, C. Mehrl
Arrangement of Materials
Materials in the collection are arranged chronologically by date of creation.
Acquisitions Information
Donated by: C. Mehrl Bennett, date unknown; Accession No. RARE.2018.0090: C. Mehrl Bennett, 2018 September
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Contains compact discs.
Access to Materials
Materials in this collection are available for use, but may be used in the Thompson Library Special Collections reading room only. Audio/visual materials and computer media may need a use copy produced before access is allowed.
Biographical Note
As of 2017, C. Mehrl Bennett is a multi-media artist, performer, and writer of fluxus scores and experimental poetry in Columbus, Ohio. She also works as a mail-artist, consultant editor and technical facilitator for Luna Bistone Prods publications, and as a contributing editor, artist and writer for arts and vispo related publications and websites. C. Mehrl Bennett is the wife of John M. Bennett, an experimental writer and former curator of the Avant Writing Collection at Ohio State University Libraries.
Scope and Contents
C. Mehrl Bennett Artwork and Visual Poetry contains small visual poetry booklets, artistamps, artist books, and printouts and compact discs of multi-media and word artwork created by C. Mehrl Bennett between 2006 and 2018. Some of the materials are collaborations with other visual artists and experimental writers. Also included are printouts of email correspondence and Bennett’s blog posts, two calendars containing Bennett’s artworks, and a copy of her resume circa 2008.
Related Materials
SPEC.RARE.0245
Mail Art and Artistamps Received by C. Mehrl Bennett
SPEC.RARE.0170
Avant Writing Publications
SPEC.RARE.CMS.0133
John M. Bennett Collection
Bennett, C. Mehrl; Artistamps; Artists' books--Ohio--Columbus--21st century; Experimental poetry, American--Ohio--Columbus--21st century; Fluxus (Group of artists); Multimedia (Art)--Ohio--Columbus--21st century; Multimedia works; Visual poetry; Visual poetry, American--Ohio--Columbus--21st century; Women artists--Ohio--Columbus--21st century; Women poets, American--Ohio--Columbus--21st century
- "Word Art" discs 1-3, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  Compact discs
- Art prints and email correspondence printouts, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Calendars of art and photos, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "John's cataract surgery" art and email correspondence printouts, 2008 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "My Kimono Book", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Compact disc
- "Words and Junk", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Resume, circa 2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Eat your Meat and Potatoes" word art and email correspondence printouts, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Two artwork printouts, collaborations with John M. Bennett and Sheila Murphy, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "Over the Sofa/Under the Skin/Inside the Head" blog post printouts, 2010 July, September (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "In Remembrance: Jan. 27, 1945 the Death Camps of Auschwitz Were Freed" visual poetry book, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Bawa Hacks" booklets, collaboration with Al Ackerman, 2011-2014 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Old Cents" visual poetry book, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Visual poetry printouts, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Asemic Shadows" visual poetry book, collaboration with Cheryl Penn, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Mail Art Congress: Picasso Gaglione and Jim Leftwich" artistamps, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Six Pictos" artistamps, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Stories" visual poetry book, collaboration with Shawn McMurtagh, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Under the Table" visual poetry book, collaboration with Cesar Espinosa, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Silhoutte" and "ART" artistamps series, 2014-2015 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Old-New-and Puddled" and "In Honor of Insignificance" artistamps, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Fourteen Pictoglyph Stories" visual poetry book, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Untitled visual poetry book, collaboration with Marilyn R. Rosenberg and Thomas M. Cassidy, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Xray Vision" visual poetry book, collaboration with John M. Bennett, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accession No. RARE.2018.0090, 2010-2018; 0.22 Cubic feet; (1) flat box
  Arrangement of Materials
  This accession is unprocessed; materials are arranged in the order received.
  Scope and Contents
  2 books of collaborative art projects that C. Mehrl Bennett contributed to, dated 2010 and 2016, and 4 folders of her artistamps created between 2015 and 2018.
  - "The Peeps Photo Project: Living the Miniature Life" collected project collaborations in book form, 2016 March (Box Accession No. RARE.2018.0090.001)
  - "Femail Artist Book (FAB)" collaborative artist book, 2010 (Box Accession No. RARE.2018.0090.001)
  - Artistamps, 2015-2018 (Box Accession No. RARE.2018.0090.001)